Gilberto Ramirez | Software Engineer



gramirez.softwareengineer@gmail.com | 🐨 github.com/Gilberto-Felipe | 💇 LinkedIn: gilbertoramirez-swe





Summary

I'm a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in Fullstack positions: React, C#, SQL Server/MySQL. I have experience in the development of content management systems and ERP applications. Open to remote positions or to be relocated abroad.

Experience

Web Developer | DPR Construction | 2021 - present [+1 year] | Remote

- Collaborated in the development and maintenance of four ERP applications: a Human Resource Planning Management, a System Management for SMS, an Asset Management Inventory, and an Employee Portal to choose the asset. My tasks involve developing UI components, Web APIs, and database views. Technologies: Javascript/ES6, React, C#, .NET Core, SQL Server, Git-GitHub, Reactstrap, Material UI (MUI), Formik, Chrome DevTools.
- Coordinated the update of documentation for integrations with third party applications. It was a continuous improvement effort every 6 months. 18 integrations were updated. 5 people participated.
- Coordinated the migration of around 1000 jobs to Activebatch, a task scheduler. The effort lasted 9 months and involved 8 engineers from different teams.

Fullstack Web Developer | GHAPPS | 2019 - 2020 [+1 year] | Colima, Mexico

• Collaborated in the development of an Information Management System. It provides information for Loro Fan, the mobile app of the University of Colima soccer team. Developed the database, the login, UI views, and the backend. The app has +100 downloads for Android. Technologies: HTML5, CSS, Javascript/ES6, JQuery, PHP, MySQL, Git-GitHub, Bootstrap, AdminLTE.

Freelance Web Developer | 2020 - present [+2 years] | Remote

• Designed, developed, deployed, and continue to do maintenance for two WordPress Websites. My client incremented 100% presence on the web.

Spanish Teacher as a Foreign Language | IH - BKC Moscow | 2015 - 2016 | Moscow, Russia Teacher of Philosophy and Humanities | 8 years of experience | Mexico and Colombia

Education

B.S. in Software Engineering | University of Colima | 2017-2021 | Colima, Mexico C# Courses | Plural Sight | 2021 | Online: Beginning Collections, Building an API with ASP.NET Core. Python for Everybody Specialization | Coursera | 2020 | Online B.A. in Philosophy | Regina Apostolorum | 2007-2011 | Rome, Italy